August Jaccaci
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
August Jaccaci papers
1889-1935 (bulk 1904-1914)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jaccaci, Augusto Floriano
7.2 cubic feet
The papers of art historican August Jaccaci measure 7.2 linear feet and date from 1889 to 1935, with the bulk of the material dating from 1904 to 1914. The collection documents Jaccaci's work as an art historian, writer, and editor, primarily during the period he researched, compiled, and published his book Noteworthy Paintings in Private American Collections. More than one-half of the collection consists of extensive correspondence to and from many notable artists, collectors, and art historians, including John La Farge, Kenyon Cox, Isabella Stewart Gardner, and Bernard Sickert concerning the research and publication of the book. The papers also house legal files, writings and notes, art collection research files, and photographs of artwork.
Biographical Note
August Florian Jaccaci was born in Fontainebleau, France in 1856. After traveling extensively in various countries including Mexico and Cuba, he settled in the United States in the early 1880s. He worked briefly as an artist in the Midwest, creating murals on commission, including a mural in the Capitol building in St. Paul, Minnesota. Jaccaci then moved to New York City and worked as art editor for Century magazine. Besides serving as art editor, he also wrote several articles and executed illustrations for the magazine. On the recommendation of artist Will H. Low he became art editor of McClure's magazine at its founding in 1896. A year later he wrote the book on his travels entitled, On the trail of Don Quixote: being a record of rambles in the ancient province of La Mancha [sic]. He left McClure's in 1902 and in 1903 began working on a major multi-volume book entitled Noteworthy Paintings in Private American Collections. Jaccaci envisioned a 15 volume set with essays about American art collections written by distinguished art historians. Though Jaccaci knew many writers, art critics, and artists through his magazine work, he was not a well-known art historian and asked artist John La Farge to be the co-editor of the book. La Farge's reputation provided access to major American collections of artwork. The publishing company Merrill and Baker was to publish the work, but it went bankrupt in 1904. Jaccaci then bought their property for his project and called it the August F. Jaccaci Co. The first volume was published in 1909, and John La Farge died in 1910. Though Jaccaci continued working on the next volume, the project failed in 1912. Besides working on this project, Jaccaci also served as editor of the "Art in America" section of Burlington Magazine from 1907 to 1910.
In 1914 August Jaccaci went to Europe on art related business. With the start of World War I, he decided to stay in France and pursue philanthropic work. He founded the Society for Protection of Children of the Frontier, and established a children's hospital, receiving many honors for his service. He died in Neuf-De-Grasse, France in 1930.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of art historican August Jaccaci measure 7.2 linear feet and date from 1889 to 1935, with the bulk of the material dating from 1904 to 1914. The collection documents Jaccaci's work as an art historian, writer, and editor, primarily during the period he researched, compiled, and published his book Noteworthy Paintings in Private American Collections. More than one-half of the collection consists of extensive correspondence to and from many notable artists, collectors, and art historians, including John La Farge, Kenyon Cox, Isabella Stewart Gardner, and Bernard Sickert concerning the research and publication of the book. The papers also house legal files, writings and notes, art collection research files, and photographs of artwork.
Correspondents include art historians, critic, artists, and art collectors, as well as publishers, photographers, printers, and agents. These letters discuss the research of famous American art collections, writing of essays for the book, and the book production and publication. There is extensive correspondence with his co-editor John La Farge, and with his employee Carl Snyder who was working in Europe. Other correspondence is with magazines, art associations, academic institutions, and French service organizations. Also included is a small amount of personal correspondence with friends and colleagues.
Legal files include contracts and legal agreements for the August F. Jaccaci Company, as well as legal agreements with John La Farge concerning the research and publication of their joint book. Writings and notes include Jaccaci's lists and notes pertaining to the Noteworthy Paintings project, as well as other miscellaneous notes. Also found are writings by John La Farge that include drafts of a book, lectures, and notes about his artwork. Writings by others in this series also include draft essays by many art historians for Jaccaci's book. For the Noteworthy Paintings project, Jaccaci created numerous research files for American art collections and collectors that would be included. These research files include lists of works of art, essays and other notes about the collection written by prominent art historians. Photographs are of works of art supporting the research files. Also found in this collection are photographs of and notes about New England stencil designs. It is unclear what the connection is between Jaccaci and the stencil designs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 5 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1895-1929, undated (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Legal Files, 1895-1911, undated (Box 5; 4 folders)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1903-1914, undated (Box 5; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 4: Art Collection Research Files, 1889, 1892, 1903-1914, undated (Box 5-7; 2.0 linear feet)
Series 5: Photographs, 1904-1912, 1928-1935, undated (Box 7-8; 0.4 linear feet)
Due to re-processing, the order of the collection varies slightly from the order of the collection on microfilm. References to the microfilm reel numbers have been added for researcher access.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects-Topical:
Art historians -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Collectors and collecting
Types of Materials:
Photographs
Names:
Cox, Kenyon, 1856-1919; Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1840-1924; La Farge, John; Sickert, Bernard, 1862-1932
Provenance
The August Jaccaci papers were purchased by the Archives of American Art from the Metropolitan Museum of Art in 1957 and microfilmed shortly after receipt.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy. Use of materials not available on microfilm requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on 35 mm microfilm reels D118-D126 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the order of the papers as re-processed varies from the order of collection on microfilm.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1895-1929, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
  More than one-half of the collection consists of Jaccaci's correspondence with everyone connected with the publication of his book Noteworthy Paintings in Private American Collections. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1903 to 1913 and is between Jaccaci and the art historians, curators, critics, and art collectors concerning the compilation of the numerous essays for the book. Correspondents include Wilhelm Bode, Kenyon Cox, Lionel Cust, William H. Downes, Max Friedlander, Roger Fry, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Jules Guiffrey, Lewis Hind, C. J. Holmes, Paul LaFond, Frank Jewett Mather, Jr., Ernst Moes, Bernhard Sickert, Oswald Siren, Mariana G. Van Rensselaer, and others. Jaccaci also corresponded with artists such as Aureliano de Beruete, Mary Cassatt, Ben Foster, Will H. Low, Harper Pennington, Rudolph Ruzicka, and Augustus Tack.
  Also included is a large amount of correspondence between John La Farge (co-editor of the book)and Jaccaci. Additional La Farge correspondence is found throughout this series as he also corresponded with many people and organizations about the book. Researchers should note some of the correspondence is signed and addressed to La Farge's secretary Grace E. Barnes. There is also a large amount of correspondence in this series with Carl Snyder, an agent working for Jaccaci in Europe. Also found is Jaccaci's correspondence with photographers, such as Frederick O. Bemm, as well as publishers, art associations, and academic institutions. Also included is a small amount of correspondence with American Magazine, Burlington Magazine, and McClure's, concerning his work as an editor.
  Scattered correspondence between Jaccaci and his friends, former co-workers, and his son August Thayer Jaccaci is found in this series. Other correspondence concerns printing and publishing, his work with French services organizations during World War One, and legal and investment matters.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of the correspondent, or, in a few instances, by topic. Unidentified letters have been arranged at the end of the series. For folders containing letters from more than one correspondent, the individual names are listed underneath the folder heading. Miscellaneous correspondence is listed after the alphabetical correspondence.
  - Academy of Political Sciences - Aldrich, Richard, 1906-1913, undated, (fr. 8-43) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Academy of Political Sciences
    Adams, B. H.
    Adams, Herbert
    Adams, Samuel Hopkins
    Aetna Real Estate
    Aldrich, Richard
  - Alexandre, Arsène, 1897-1906, undated, (fr. 44-98) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Allan, Alice R. B. - Anderson Auction Company, 1907-1913, (fr. 99-132) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Allan, Alice R. B.
    American Academy in Rome
    American Art Association
    American Express Company
    American Magazine
    Anderson, H. B.
    Anderson Auction Company
  - Andrew, George T. (John T. Andrew & Son), 1906-1913, (3 folders; fr. 133-384) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Angus, R. B. - Atterbury, Grosvernor, 1897-1913, (fr. 385-447) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Angus, R. B.
    Armstrong, Mr. & Mrs. Charles F.
    Armstrong, Miss May H.
    Armstrong, Sir Walter
    Atterbury, Grosvenor
  - Balcarres, Lord - Bates, A. E., 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 449-477) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Balcarres, Lord
    Baldry, A. L.
    Baldwin, H. & Jessie
    Bank of Montreal
    Barbour, Thomas J.
    Barse, George R.
    Bartlett, Paul Wayland
    Bates, A. E.
  - Bates, C. E., 1913, undated, (fr. 478-512) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Beard, Ruth - Bell, Marion Mason, 1903-1914, undated, (fr. 513-555) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Beard, Ruth
    Beatty, John W.
    Beauregard, H. E.
    Beaux, Cecelia
    Behr, Evelyn Schley
    Bell, C. H.
    Bell, Malcolm
    Bell, Marion Mason
  - Bemm, Frederick O., 1903-1904, (2 folders; fr.556-617) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Bénédité Family - Berenson, Bernard, 1896-1908, undated, (fr. 714-771) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Bénédité Family
    Beniot, Camille
    Berenson, Bernard
  - Beruete, Aureliano de, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 772-820) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Betts, Courtland - Blanc, Edouard, 1896-1914, (fr. 821-834) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Betts, Cortland
    Biddy, C. Howard
    Binkerd, Robert S.
    Blackburn, Kate
    Blackeslee, T. J.
    Blair & Company
    Blanc, Edouard (fr. 618-632)
  - Blanc, M., 1897, undated, (fr. 633-703) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland - Boddy, Alexander A., 1898-1912, undated, (fr. 704-713) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Blashfield, Edwin Howland
    Blay, Gaston
    Bliss, Anna B.
    Blommers, Bernardus J.
    Blumenschein, Ernest Leonard
    Boddy, Alexander A., (fr. 835-836)
  - Bode, Wilhelm, 1903-1907, (2 folders; fr. 837-950) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Bodenhausen, Baron E. von - Bowles, J. M., 1897-1911, undated, (fr. 951-987) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Bodenhausen, Baron E. von
    Bogart, William
    Bolling, Anna P.
    Boronda, Lester D.
    Bouchot, Henri
    Boutet de Monvel, Louis M.
    Boutroux, E.
    Bowles, J. M.
  - Bradley, William H., 1896-1913, (fr. 988-1035) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Brangwyn, Frank - Breck, Joseph, 1903-1912, (fr. 1036-1053) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Brangwyn, Frank
    Breck, Joseph
  - Bredius, Abraham, 1903-1914, (2 folders, fr. 1054-1140) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Brennan, Alfred - Brownell, Adelia & William Crary, 1896-1913, 1928, undated, (fr. 1141-1193) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Brennan, Alfred
    Brewer, Cyrus & Co.
    Brewster, William T.
    Britton, James
    Brockett, Helen F.
    Brogi, Sig.
    Bromhead, H. W.
    Brown, A. V. V.
    Brown, Thomas
    Brown, J. Romaine
    Brownell, Mathilda
    Brownell, Adelia & William Crary
  - Brunetière, Ferdinand & Sylvie - Burlingham, Charles C., 1897-1913, (fr. 1194-1229) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Brunetière, Ferdinand & Sylvie
    Brush, George De Forest
    Bryn Mawr College
    Burger, W. M.
    Burlingham, Charles C.
  - Burlington Magazine, 1905-1911, (2 folders, fr. 1230-1360) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Burroughs, Bryson - Byrne, James, 1896-1914, undated, (fr. 1361-1386) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Burroughs, Bryson
    Burroughs, Caroline B.
    Burroughs, Edith Woodman
    Bush-Brown, Margaret Lesley
    Butler, Howard Russell
    Butler, Nicholas Murray
    Byrne, Helen M.
    Byrne, James
  - Caffin, Charles H. - Carter, Morris, 1901-1914, (fr. 1388-1418) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Caffin, Charles H.
    Cagnola, Guido
    Canadian Art Club
    Candee, Da Forest
    Cantalamessa, Hector
    Cardon, C. Leon
    Carli, H. A.
    Carrel, Alexis
    Carrington, Fitzroy
    Carter, Morris
  - Cary, Edward and Elizabeth Luther, 1906-1911, undated, (fr. 1419-1469) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Cassatt, Mary, 1904-1909, undated, (fr. 1477-1497) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Case, William Warren - Caw, James L., 1896-1909, (fr. 1470-1519) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Case, William Warren
    Cassierer, Bruno
    Castaigne, A.
    Cather, Willa
    Cattell, Mr.
    Caw, James L.
  - Chadwick, F. E. - Chambolle, 1896-1913, (fr. 1520-1555) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Chadwick, F. E.
    Chamberlain, Arthur B.
    Chambers, John Armstrong
    Chambolle
  - Champeau, Lawrence X., 1911-1914, undated, (fr. 1556-1600) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Chapman, John Jay, 1897-1914, undated, (fr. 1601-1652) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Chassériau, A. - Colvin, Sidney, 1897-1912, (fr. 1653-1679) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Chassériau, A. (fr. 1498-1499)
    Chew, Beverly
    Chicago Art Institute
    Child, Edwin Burrage
    Chivers, Cedric
    Church, S. H.
    Clifford, William
    Colby, F. G.
    Coles, Ann Cadwallader
    Colnaghi, Martin A.
    Columbia University
    Colvin, Sidney
  - Comte, Jules, 1904-1911, (fr. 1680-1763) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Conway, Sir Martin, 1904-1916, (2 folders; fr. 1768-1840) (Box 1, Reel D118)
  - Cook, Herbert - Cooper, William A., 1904-1912, undated, (fr. 1841-1885) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Cook, Herbert
    Cook, Theodore A.
    Cooper, William A.
  - Coppi, Signor - Coudert, Frederic R., 1904-1926, (fr. 1886-1925) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Coppi, Signor
    Cordier, Oscar
    Cortissoz, Royal
    Cossio, Manuel B.
    Costantini, Prof.
    Coudert, Frederic R.
  - Coudor, Lucien - Cowles, Gardner & Genevieve, 1896-1920, (fr. 1926-1937) (Box 1, Reel D118)
    Coudor, Lucien
    Countryman, Gratia
    Cowles, Gardner & Genevieve
  - Cox, Kenyon, 1903-1914, (3 folders; fr. 1-242) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Coxe, Reginald C. - Cushing, Howard, 1897-1913, (fr. 243-289) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Coxe, Reginald C.
    Crittenden, Lillian & Walter H.
    Crowe, Eyre
    Culin, S.
    Curtis, Charles B.
    Curtis, Ralph
    Cushing, Howard
  - Cust, Lionel, 1903-1905, undated, (fr. 290-326) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Davey, Emma Stiles - Dodd, Frank H., 1898-1916, (fr. 328-367) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Davey, Emma Stiles
    Davies, Gerald S.
    Davis, Charles Q.
    De la Croix, Jeanne
    Dell, Robert
    Dick, Elizabeth
    Dimier, Louis
    Dodd, Frank H.
  - Dodgson, Campbell - Doubleday, Page & Co., 1904-1914, (fr. 368-386) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Dodgson, Campbell Dotson, J. T. Doubleday, Page & Co.
  - Downes, William H., 1904-1911, (fr. 387-436) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Dunn, Gano - Duveen, Henry, 1904-1914, (fr. 437-477) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Dunn, Gano
    Dunne, Walter
    Dun's Reviews
    Durand-Gréville, E.
    Durel, A.
    Duret, Theodore
    Duveen, Henry
  - Eaton, Mary - Ends of the Earth Club, 1906-1914, undated, (fr. 479-492) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Eaton, Mary
    Eden, Henry J.
    Emmett, Grenville T.
    Ends of the Earth Club
  - Ferguson, Edith - Forepaugh, Alice, 1896-1913, undated, (fr. 494-527) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Ferguson, Edith
    Field, Mr.
    Firmin, M.
    Fletcher, Jefferson B.
    Florian, Mr.
    Foote, Mary
    Forepaugh, Alice
  - Foster, Ben, 1903-1904, undated, (fr. 528-549) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Foundation France-Americaine - Freer, Charles L., 1903-1924, (fr. 550-588) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Foundation France-Americaine
    Fraser, W. A.
    Frazer, Julia
    Freer, Charles L.
  - French, Daniel Chester - French Line, 1907-1914, (fr. 589-629) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    French, Daniel Chester
    French, William M.
    French-American Book Plan
    French Line
  - French Service Organizations, 1914-1918, undated, (fr. 1612-1649) (Box 1, Reel D123)
  - Friedlander, Max, 1903-1912, undated, (fr. 630-676) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Frimmel, Theodore von - Frost, George A., 1896-1904, undated, (fr. 677-719) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Frimmel, Theodore von
    Frizzoni, Gustavo
    Fromuth, Charles H.
    Frost, George A.
  - Fry, Roger, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 720-787) (Box 1, Reel D119)
  - Fullerton, W. M. - Furman, Virginia D. H., 1897, 1925, (fr. 788-793) (Box 1, Reel D119)
    Fullerton, W. M.
    Furman, Virginia D. H.
  - Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1903-1904, undated, (5 folders; fr. 795-924) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Garnsey, Elmer G. - Gillet, Louis, 1897-1914, undated, (fr. 925-962) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Garnsey, Elmer G.
    Gary, Elbert
    Gatringer, Joseph
    Geffroy, Gustave
    Gibson, D. C.
    Gilbert, Cass
    Gillet, Louis
  - Gillis Press (Walter Gillis), 1903-1906, (4 folders; fr. 963-1199) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Giraudon, A. - Gluck, Gustave, 1896-1906, (fr. 1200-1211) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Giraudon, A.
    Gluck, Gustave
  - Goodrich, Joseph King, 1910-1912, (fr. 1212-1241) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Goodyear, William H. - Gronau, Georg, 1904-1912, undated, (fr. 1242-1286) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Goodyear, William H.
    Gordon, Richard
    Graham, Florence
    Gregory, Eliot
    Gronau, Georg
  - Guiffrey, Jean & Jules, 1904-1914, undated, (3 folders; fr. 1287-1414) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Gutekunst, G. - Harriman, Elizabeth, 1895-1929, undated, (fr. 1415-1453) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Gutekunst, G.
    Halford, G. V.
    Halsey, R. J.
    Hambridge, Jay
    Hamerton, E.
    Hamilton, E. W. D.
    Hamp, Pierre
    Hapgood, Isabel F.
    Hardy, Katherine E.
    Hardy, Walter B.
    Harriman, Elizabeth
  - Hart, Charles Henry - Hill, James J., 1898-1914, undated, (fr. 1454-1498) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Hart, Charles Henry
    Hauser, A.
    Havemeyer, L. W.
    Hay, Clare S.
    Healy, A. Augustus
    Heim, Aimee L. F.
    Heinemann, William
    Herrick, Robert
    Hesler, Albert
    Hess, Tessie
    Hill, James J.
  - Hillard, Mary, 1908-1914, (2 folders; fr. 1499-1600) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Hind, Lewis, 1902-1908, (fr. 1601-1634) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Hirth, Friedrich - Historischer Verlung Baumgartel, 1904-1909, (fr. 1635-1639) (Box 2, Reel D119)
    Hirth, Friedrich
    Historischer Verlung Baumgartel
  - Hofstede de Groot, C., 1904, (fr. 1644-1705) (Box 2, Reel D119)
  - Holmes, C. J., 1904-1911, (5 folders; 1706-1849, D120: 1-115) (Box 2, Reel D119-D120)
  - Holmes, Richard R. - Holt, Henry & Co., 1897-1912, (fr. 116-125) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Holmes, Richard R.
    Holroyd, Sir Charles
    Holsmann, Wilhelm
    Holt, Henry & Co.
  - Horne, Herbert P., 1904-1912, undated, (fr. 126-196) (Box 2, Reel D120)
  - Hotel Continental - Hulin de Loo, Georges, 1897-1914, (fr. 197-262) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Hotel Continental (Reel D118, fr. 1764-1767)
    Houlton Book Company
    Howells, Mildred
    Hubbard, Elbert
    Hubbard, Gardiner G.
    Hulin de Loo, Georges
  - Huneker, James - Hymans, Henri, 1904-1910, (fr. 263-296) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Huneker, James
    Huntington, Archer W.
    Hutt, Henry
    Hymans, Henri
  - Ingersoll-Smouse, Florence - Ingres, M., 1908-1913, (fr. 298-327) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Ingersoll-Smouse, Florence
    Ingres, M.
  - Isham, Samuel - Ito, Soken, 1903-1904, 1913, undated, (fr. 328-372) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Isham, Samuel
    Ito, Soken
  - Jaccaci, August Florian to his son Thayer Jaccaci, 1903-1904, undated, (fr. 374-471) (Box 2, Reel D120)
  - Jackson, Emily - Justi, Carl K., 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 472-511) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Jackson, Emily
    Jackson, A. V. Williams
    James, A. H.
    Johnson, Bettina Eastman
    Johnson, John G.
    Johnston, W. A.
    Justi, Carl K.
  - Kaemmerer, Ludwig - Kessler, Graf, 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 513-548) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Kaemmerer, Ludwig
    Kelly, Annie
    Kendall, William Sergeant
    Kennedy, E. G.
    Kent, Henry W.
    Kent, Jessie Adams
    Kessler, Graf
  - Kleinberger, F. - Kristeller, Paul, 1904-1910, (fr. 549-585) (Box 2, Reel D120)
    Kleinberger, F.
    Knaufft, Ernest
    Kraus, Filiph
    Kristeller, Paul
  - La Farge, C. Grant, 1896, 1911, (fr. 586-589) (Box 2, Reel D120)
  - La Farge, John, 1900-1911, undated, (11 folders; fr. 590-1443) (Box 2, Reel D120)
  - La Farge, Margaret - La Farge, Oliver, 1898-1914, (fr. 1714-1738) (Box 3, Reel D120)
    La Farge, Margaret
    La Farge, Oliver
  - LaFenestre, Georges, 1904-1909, undated, (fr. 2-30) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - LaFond, Paul, 1904-1913, (3 folders, fr. 31-266) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Lamb, Charles R. - Lange, Ellis E., 1897-1910, (fr. 267-289) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Lamb, Charles R.
    Lambert, John, Jr.
    Lange, Ellis E.
  - Lanier, Henry & Robert, 1897-1912, (fr. 290-337) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Lasneret, Alfred - Lawson, Ernest, 1906-1926, (fr. 352-386) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Lasneret, Alfred
    Lathrop, Francis
    Laurinburg Normal & Industrial Institute
    Lawson, Ernest
  - Legal and Investment Correspondence, 1906-1914, undated, (fr. 512-554) (Box 3, Reel D123)
  - Leichtman Brothers - Linson, Corwin Knapp & Lyman S., 1897-1913, (fr. 387-426) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Leichtman Brothers
    Library of Congress
    Lincoln National Bank
    Linson, Corwin Knapp & Lyman S.
  - Lippman, Adeline - Lockwood, Wilton, 1907-1912, undated, (fr. 427-449) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Lippman, Adeline
    Lippman, F. W.
    Liscomb, Christine
    Lizotte, May
    Lockwood, Wilton
  - Loeser, Charles, 1903-1904, undated, (fr. 450-475) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Low, Will. H., 1903-1907, (fr. 476-491) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Lowell, Orson - Ludwig, Gustav, 1904, undated, (fr. 492-511) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Lowell, Orson
    Ludington, Katharine
    Ludwig, Gustav
  - Macbeth, D. - McCarter, Henry, 1896-1913, undated, (fr. 556-596) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Macbeth, D.
    McCarther, Henry
  - McClure, S. S. (McClure's Magazine), 1903-1910, undated, (fr. 597-618) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - McCraigh, Elizabeth - MacVeagh, Charles, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 619-644) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    McCraigh, Elizabeth
    McFarland, J. H.
    McIlvaine, Clarence
    McKay, William